<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="gr_web_shm">
    <copyright>
        Copyright © 2019 Erik De Rijcke

        Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person
        obtaining a copy of this software and associated documentation files
        (the "Software"), to deal in the Software without restriction,
        including without limitation the rights to use, copy, modify, merge,
        publish, distribute, sublicense, and/or sell copies of the Software,
        and to permit persons to whom the Software is furnished to do so,
        subject to the following conditions:

        The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the
        next paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial
        portions of the Software.

        THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND,
        EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF
        MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND
        NONINFRINGEMENT. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS
        BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN
        ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING FROM, OUT OF OR IN
        CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER DEALINGS IN THE
        SOFTWARE.
    </copyright>

    <interface name="gr_web_shm_buffer" version="1">
        <request name="attach">
            <description summary="Transfer array buffer ownership to the compositor.">
                Attaches an HTML5 array buffer to the compositor. After attaching, the array buffer ownership is passed
                to the compositor main thread. The array buffer can not be used for writing anymore by the client as
                per HTML5 Transferable objects spec.

                The pixel format of the attached array buffer must always be RGBA8888 as per HTML5 ImageData spec.
                Stride must always equal width.
            </description>
            <arg name="contents" type="fd" summary="An HTML5 array buffer to attach to the compositor."/>
        </request>
        <event name="detach">
            <description summary="Transfer array buffer ownership to the client.">
                Detaches a previously attached HTML5 array buffer from the compositor and returns it to the client so
                it can be reused again for writing. After detaching, the array buffer ownership is passed from
                the compositor main thread back to the client.
            </description>
            <arg name="contents" type="fd" summary="An HTML5 array buffer, detached from the compositor"/>
        </event>
    </interface>

    <interface name="gr_web_shm" version="1">
        <description summary="shared memory support">
            A singleton global object that provides support for shared memory through HTML5 array buffers.

            Clients can create wl_buffer objects using the create_buffer request.
        </description>

        <request name="create_web_array_buffer">
            <description summary="create an HTML5 array buffer">
                Create a gr_web_shm_buffer object.
            </description>
            <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="gr_web_shm_buffer" summary="web shm buffer to create"/>
        </request>

        <request name="create_buffer">
            <description summary="create a buffer">
                Create a wl_buffer object from a web_array_buffer so it can be used with a surface.
            </description>
            <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="wl_buffer" summary="buffer to create"/>
            <arg name="web_array_buffer" type="object" interface="gr_web_shm_buffer"
                 summary="The gr_web_array_buffer to wrap"/>
            <arg name="width" type="int" summary="Buffer width, in pixels."/>
            <arg name="height" type="int" summary="Buffer height, in pixels."/>
        </request>
    </interface>
</protocol>